# Mohamed Shaheed A

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India



mohamedshaheed8055@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/mohamed-shaheed-a-9497731b3

### Summary

Passionate web developer experience in developing quality web applications using skills like HTML (Worked on input forms, iframes, elements & attributes like a,h1,div,class,id,src,href etc..) ,CSS (Worked on flexbox & grid, media queries, positions, float, z-index, applying styles using class and ids etc..), JAVASCRIPT(Worked on arrays, objects, JSON, ES6 features, arrow functions, ajax (post,get), map, find, filter, DOM, let, const, for/of, promises etc..),React is(Worked on components, useState, useEffects etc..)

Projects:

#### 1.CresChat:

It was my final year college project, Basically our project was a organized social media for students. our primary goal is to make a interaction between students and professors in our website, in which you can post questions, doubts and professors can clear your doubts and questions. And another feature is professors can post something use full posts like related to education articles, blogs ect...

Technologies Worked With:

Frontend Tools: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Backend Tools: Node.js, Express.js,

Database: mongo DB.

#### 2.Tesla clone:

It was a Tesla website UI clone.

Frontend Tools: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap, React js

#### 3. Swiggy menu clone:

It was a swiggy menu section UI clone.

Frontend Tools: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap, React is

#### 4.E-commerce website:

It was a basic ecommerce website developed by react js Frontend Tools: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap, React js

## **Experience**



#### Full-stack Developer

The Sparks Foundation

May 2021 - Jun 2021 (2 months) Project: BASIC BANKING SYSTEM

My Task was to create and deploy a banking web application with certain functions like transferring money, showing Transaction details, balance ect...

Technologies used:

Frontend Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Backend Tools: Node.js, Express.js,

Database: Mongo DB



### Web Developer

**Exposys Data Labs** 

Apr 2021 - May 2021 (2 months)

Task: Create a website

Turn design pages and specific components into a Functional website using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

Technologies used:

Frontend Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript,

### **Education**



### BSA Crescent Institute of Science and Technology

BCA, Cloud technology and information security 2018 - 2021

## **Licenses & Certifications**





Web Developer Internship - Exposys Data Labs



Full-Stack Developer - The Sparks Foundation

#### **Skills**

HTML • Front-end Development • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • JavaScript • React.js • Bootstrap jQuery